[Music]
Uh good evening everyone. like to call
the finance committee meeting to order.
We have three resolutions and as you can
see a litany of new ordinances. So we
will get through these starting with
temporary resolution 8725 coming through
water water pollution. Mr. Wing.
>> Yes. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Uh, this
resolution allows the mayor to prepare
and submit a grant application uh to the
Ohio Department of Development to
replace indoor lighting and uh replace
boilers and fix other HVAC issues at the
South Water Plant. Uh, the South Water
Plant's been experiencing some
insulation and HVAC issues uh that have
led to pipes freezing and bursting and
causing some floods inside the plant.
Um, it's also this also led to increased
utility bills as well. Um so the total
project will not exceed 525,000.
Uh the grant is for 250,000 and our
local share will not exceed 275,000.
And uh those will be coming from
budgeted water revenue funds. And um
with that I'll let the administration
add on or uh they can answer any
questions.
>> Did he sum it up or you want to you want
to add?
>> I think he summed it up just nicely. I
will just add that we are asking for
suspension on this just because the
grant is due.
>> Okay.
>> It's due October 31st. So, we will be
suspending tonight and I have
Councilwoman Tener as my second.
>> Any other questions
about this one? I'm just going to throw
out my two cents. We can't return this
lemon called the Southwater Plant at
this point.
>> Way overdue on the return. All right. We
can just continue to look for grants to
help upgrade it.
>> Okay.
All right.
Temporary resolution 8825.
This is coming through council the whole
uh who wants to
address this one.
>> Service safety director Woody, would you
do?
>> I certainly will. So, as I think most of
you are probably aware, the Lancaster
Sherman Rotary has spent the last
several years uh adopting what we refer
to as center alley. And they've done
murals, they've done lighting, they've
done an archway. Uh there are currently
beautiful mums in the in the middle of
the alley. And they have taken that on
as a service club where they constantly
maintain and beautify that area. So what
we are going to what we are asking
council as a whole to do is just
recognize the Lancaster Sherman Rotary
Club in giving them an honorary naming
of that alley, the Sherman Rotary Alley.
It is honorary only. It's not not a
legal name change, but just a nice way
to say thank you, recognize the SH
Lancaster Sherman Rotary for all they
have done and continue to do for uh the
downtown area and specifically the
center alley. Any
questions?
No.
Okay. So, I'll make the motion when we
get to the regular meeting, you'll
second and then we'll vote from there.
Perfect.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Temporary resolution 8925
coming through safety. Mr. Bisjack.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chair. Uh if if
council remembers here and the committee
remembers uh I believe it was a month
ago or a few weeks ago uh recently uh
council approved legislation to go out
for RFP and RFQS to find uh somebody to
come up with a professional design for
the Ed Road firehouse. Um that person or
that firm has been selected app
architecture. So, this legislation
tonight is continuing that process and
basically allowing the service safety
director to once again enter into a
contract with ARP app architecture not
to exceed $500,000.
Uh, that is all this legislation is
seeking to accomplish is authorizing the
SSD to enter into a contract. Nothing
more. That's all, Mr. Chair. Thank you.
And I have council member Tiner as my
second and we're going three readings on
this one.
>> Any questions?
>> Yes, Mr.
uh know the budget for this building,
construction budget.
>> No, it's not been designed yet. Um as
soon as it's designed, we'll have a
better idea of what the potential price
will be.
>> How many square foot are we looking at?
Do you know, Jane?
>> Let him do it.
>> Well, thank you for the question. uh
preliminary square foot for a station, a
similar station with the the needs um
that would meet the city of Lancaster
fire departments. It's approximately
12,000 square feet.
>> Okay. Yeah, that sounds about right.
Then you'll probably be in the $5
million range then when it's all said
and done.
>> Let's hope so.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
>> It's great. Um, have we resolved all
property or environmental issues for
that location yet?
>> There are no environmental issues with
that location. Um, that was the reason
for the the long pause and delay this
summer. Um, we hired an environmental
um, firm to do an environmental
assessment and study of the property.
Um, and we're able to take that
information, um, have the city
engineering department go over it with
us and conclude that we have no issues
building on that site.
>> Okay. And that includes the electric
lines, things like that.
>> That is correct.
>> It it makes it challenging because
there's a sewer trunk main and the um,
easement, but um, I've been assured that
we'll have enough space to put the
firehouse in as needed. Okay.
>> Thank you. Now, we will have to raise
raise um
elevation. Thank you. I lost my train of
thought. We will have to raise the
elevation. However, uh our city engineer
said that it's best to do that with the
project. Um so, we haven't really taken
steps to do that ahead of time because
that'll be part of the project.
>> Do we know an estimated cost for how
much that will increase the cost
overall?
>> I have not seen that broken out yet. Was
that broken out in any of the costs that
you've seen?
>> No, not yet. We're still in the design
phase and we don't have enough
information to go out and get
contractors or engineers estimates as of
yet.
>> We have delivered some uh soil to the
site um which was uh put there what a
couple months ago.
>> Correct.
>> Not not enough, but we have some already
on site.
>> Will that impact the timeline as far as
getting it prepared, things like that?
>> Some of those are unknown. raising it up
is going to impact the cost,
>> but I don't think it'll impact the
timeline because I think that that was
already Yes. included in their project
timeline.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Any other questions on that one?
Okay. All right. All right, we're going
to move on to ordinances starting with
temporary ordinance 5725
is coming through finance
which is me and this the city treasurer
pay ordinance
SSD Woody do you want to go over these
or this one
>> or
>> I'm more than happy.
>> I can go over that one. This is a
recommendation from my office. Uh when
we did uh elected official salary
adjustments last year, the treasur was
not included in that uh because the term
was still ongoing. Uh in order to adjust
uh salaries for any elected office, we
have to do so before the new term
begins, which it will begin January 1.
Uh I looked at the
adjustments we made to the mayor, the u
auditor, law director, etc. and uh
looked at the average increase we did
for those positions. So the first two
years you'll see that average uh was
included and then the final two years
are set at 3%. Uh, so this is we had the
goal all along to try to get that
treasurer salary at the $40,000 mark
trying to attract qualified people. Um,
a lot of hesitation for this job is it's
a part-time job and but we still need
qualified people and the salary was
awfully low and I looked at comparable
cities uh similar size. Some are
significantly higher, there's some
significantly lower. Um, I know what our
treasur's responsibilities are and
they're they're
uh part-time does work, but they're
still challenging and treasur needs to
be competent and capable. And I am
making this recommendation based on what
we did with the previous elected
positions and and based on the goal to
get to $40,000 by the end of this term,
the next term.
>> All right. Any questions?
So then you'll maybe get a confident
treasure instead of Bob and I. So
>> I'm hoping for at least the next term,
right?
>> At least the next time, right?
>> All right. Um,
did we get a refund? Is that what we
were asking for?
>> No, you don't need a refund. Um, okay.
So were your three readings on that? Mr.
Als be my second.
No other questions. We're moving on to
temporary ordinance 5825 coming through
the law committee. Miss Crates.
>> Yes. Thank you. Uh, this legislation
helps the city maintain compliance with
a new requirement recently passed by the
state requiring we adopt and enact a
cyber security program by January 1st of
2026. Our IT department drafted the
city's program which includes city
offices department's municipal court and
port authority. And it should be noted
that the cyber security programs and
related records are not considered part
of public records under Ohio law.
Stephanie, did you want to add anything
to that?
>> No, I think your last point there was
the most important. Um, I asked the IT
department for their program so I could
attach it and they were like, "You can't
have it." And I was like, "Oh, yeah,
that makes sense. We don't want that to
be public." So, um, I'm sure they will
go over the finer points with you if you
would like that, but it's not a public
record, so nobody's ever going to have a
a physical copy of that, FYI. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Mr. Bischeck is my second.
We'll go three readings.
>> Okay. Thank you. Any questions?
Seeing none, we'll move on to temporary
ordinance 5925 coming through code
enforcement with Mr. Sully.
Um, Chas, let our city planner
tell us what's going on here.
>> Good evening. Um, Arbor Homes is
requested to change the zoning at zero
Rainbow Drive. This is located north of
Rainbow Drive and west of Lancaster
Thornville Road or State Route 188. Um,
the current zoning is within the city of
Lancaster. It's a PUD, a planned unit
development.
um and they would like to change it to a
residential medium density district.
This change of zoning was approved by
the planning commission on October 9th.
So, just a little more background, the
original um project that was going to
take place at the time was with our old
zoning and I think it was an RS3
um but it was it correlated with that
medium residential medium density and
then they did a PUD overlay.
However, that development was never
developed. There was no standards that
were ever um designed for that. So now
this so now there's no developmental
standards for that PUD.
Um so this would just kind of give
zoning and development standards for
that district.
>> If I would, Mr. Chair, I just want to
make one correction on the copy that's
in your packet. Uh the second whereas
says voted unanimously
that has been updated. I think the clerk
has the corrected copy. They voted to
recommend but it was not unanimous.
There was one uh no vote during the
planning commission meeting. I just want
to make sure you're clear of that.
Okay. Does anyone have any questions?
Like this first I heard of this was when
we got the packet. Unless I'm
>> I was at the meeting and I can tell you
that there when we have our public
hearing
>> the neighbors
>> get ready.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
it it there wasn't a person at that
public hearing that was in favor of the
project. So we're kind of getting ahead
of the this was just to approve the the
zoning. So but what's coming
>> is I I guess that was my question.
>> Not going to be well received. This is
more we had not heard anything from
zoning the blue.
>> We had not heard any I I I know it went
before planning commission but we hadn't
heard anything from economic development
or
>> or from Stephanie Bosco on this one.
Right.
>> Correct.
>> Um this is a project we spoke about at
length. Uh this was uh
Mr. Luckenberg's question the size of
the lots and and that's certainly one of
the things that members of the
neighborhood had questions about.
Um we will have a public hearing and
they'll be able to come in and speak to
you about their concerns. Uh but uh this
is actually
similar
uh zoning as to what was already in
place with the PUD. Uh it was RS3 under
the old code with the PUD overlay as
Chasin stated and this is RM
>> D. Yes, RMD.
>> It's our new code. So
>> okay,
>> planning commission's done their
portion. It now comes to council and
then council will do their
>> right. I the one that you were asking
about is the one on Sheridan Drive.
>> Yeah,
>> we've we've talked about all these
developments.
>> We I talked about this one as well.
>> Yeah.
>> And I
through some part of that, so I
apologize. It doesn't sound familiar to
me whatsoever.
>> So I was just curious.
>> Well, seeing the topography on this, I
don't know how in the world they're
going to do 40 foot wide lots. There's
this this is a very steeply
uh graded site and I I I don't know how
this layout's going to work, but we'll
let them figure it out, I guess.
>> Yes. Not not our issue. We did talk
about this before. I'm really like
>> I'm trying to think about when if we've
talked about it because we haven't had a
tiff. Um there was the PUD. The new
design is a new developer. It's it's not
uh much different from what had been
there previously.
Um but I had not brought it up because
it has
some projects are clearly have legs and
some projects have legs but it's not
that clear. So when they came in to
clean up the zoning I was like oh I
guess we're moving a lot quicker than
than we have um been with that.
>> That's fine. I'm it's I get the process.
I I just don't remember ever having the
conversation about that piece cuz when I
first saw it I was like, "Well, wait a
minute. Is that in the city?" So,
>> yeah,
>> I feel like I was just looking at it for
the first time. So,
>> you may have been. Yes.
>> So, I do know we've talked about it. Not
uh I don't know that we talked in depth
about it. We did certainly didn't have
legislation, but I remember the give and
take between Steve and and I about it.
And uh but it it's also been presented
at multiple committee meetings.
>> Yeah.
um over time uh and it's been in the
cities since the 70s.
>> Yeah. And there's been a variety of
interest in the last just in the last
years that I've been here. Um so like I
said, sometimes that they're not really
keeping me they're not telling me
exactly what they're doing and the next
thing you know they're they're changing
zoning. You know, it really was just a
clean up to get it to get it taken care
of.
>> So,
>> okay. Sorry to make that really
>> longer than it needed to be, but
confusing.
>> I definitely don't remember it. So,
okay. My apologies. Any other questions
on that one?
>> So, Mr. Sully, you have three readings
with Miss Hoop as your second.
>> Perfect.
>> You want my second?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. All right. Thank you. Temporary
ordinance 6025 also coming through code
enforcement zoning. Mr. Sully,
>> I'll let Chasine come back up.
>> Okay. So, this is the revised uh version
of the short-term rentals after it was
tabled on
um August 25th.
If you would like, I can kind of go
through a an overview of what was
changed on it.
Okay.
Okay. So, besides the language and
formatting revisions, um, which you'll
find throughout the code, the following
things were amended. So, 1131.01A1
allowing for one application to be
submitted if multiple short-term rentals
are located within the same short-term
rental premises. Uh, the reasoning
behind this was to avoid the multiple
fees for the same property.
113101C
was amended, changing the renewal
process to be in two-year increments
instead of one to once again take away
some of the hardship and fees from the
short-term rental applicants, but to
still maintain diligence and checking to
ensure safety and code requirements are
being upheld.
113103A6,
the section on on street public parking
was emitted. The original thought behind
this was to try and prevent uh all the
street parking from being taken up by
short-term rentals renters. However, um
we cannot prevent or enforce parking
restrictions on public rideways.
113103A88,
a provision was added that allows
applicants to submit background checks
that had previously been carried out
within the past 12 months. This falls in
line with our current vendor
requirements which allow for this
provision.
113104D,
appropriate warnings to tenants or
renters regarding the existence of
security cameras must be posted on the
premises. 113104H,
a provision was added stating that
short-term rentals shall only be rented
to individuals 18 years or older.
113105E.
A provision was added to grounds for
denial stating the short-term rental or
short-term rental premises does not have
adequate fire protection or otherwise
presents a risk of bodily injury by way
of fire.
uh definitions were added for short
short-term rental and short-term rental
premises.
>> Any questions for
Miss Carter?
I'll just add that all these changes
were either from council members
themselves or and or the public. Uh so
we had a lot of requests to revisit some
of these uh particular uh points that
Chaz went over but um we adjust them
based on that input. So there there's
significant change from the original
document you saw um a while back.
>> Okay. So,
>> three readings.
>> You know what we're doing with So,
tonight are we going to remove the So,
we're going to remove the previous
>> going to remove it from the table and
there'll be a motion to withdraw.
>> Okay.
>> 3125.
>> Perfect. All right. Any other questions
on that one?
Seeing none, we'll move on. Uh the next
six
pieces all coming through finance. all
of the pay ordinances
starting with temporary ordinance 6125.
Um, you received an email from SSD Woody
with all of those and then I will
let you highlight what you want and then
we can take questions and then if you
just if you want to go through each one
individually, it's fine. I'm just not
going to stop you and introduce
everyone.
>> Okay.
So, I did send out an email to all of
council with with the highlights in the
management ordinance itself. I don't
think you're going to see any major
highlights other than um
I will say in section two of the
management ordinance. Uh we do have an
update because we uh forgot to budget
for 27 pays instead of 26. So that will
be a difference. Um
so you will see in change we will have
an amended version for you at the next
meeting. Um,
in the non-management ordinance again,
um, I provided a note to you. If you
recall earlier this year, we did a
resolution for
or rather an ordinance to put all of our
inspection, our engineering inspection
fees into one account so that we can
have one person doing the public
improvement inspections. That's going to
be our current rideway inspector out of
engineering. So, you will know that um
in the engineering section of the non-UN
pay ordinance, when the rightaway
manager is acting as the public
improvement inspector, there will be an
out of range pay for him to do those
inspections so that he's paid at a
higher rate than doing his regular ride
ofway inspections.
Um
I'm trying to remember all of the things
that I sent to you.
I
the wording again. I sent you all a
redline copy in your email so that you
would see exactly everything that was
changing. There was a lot of text that
referred to
benefits that had been passed in last
year's ordinance that we just took out
of this ordinance because it's very
wordy. And because it was already passed
by council, we just put it into the
policy procedure manual because it had
already been passed so it need to be
passed again. So you'll see all of those
red lines that are coming through.
And I think the only other thing in the
non-union ordinance was in our IT
department, we are changing the there
were two IT specialist twos. We're going
to have one IT specialist two now and
then we're going to add one IT
specialist three. So we're just changing
a pay range for one of those IT
specialists. And I believe that those
were all of the highlights that I had
sent to you in the email this weekend.
I'm open to any questions,
>> Miss Tiner. I'm
>> I'm so sorry. I I just cannot remember.
So, when we moved the one individual
from utilities to zoning, are we
replacing that person or are we not
going to replace that position?
>> We are not replacing that position in
utilities.
>> Okay. Thank you. I couldn't remember.
Thank you.
>> No problem.
>> I know this is six pieces. Has everybody
gotten a chance to look at that original
email? Any want to have any questions?
>> I will just say to Becky's point, I
failed to take it out of this pay
ordinance. So, I will do that for your
amended uh
>> Oh, okay. Amended ordinance. I just
couldn't remember an oversight on my
part. I just looked at it and it's still
in there. So, I will take that out
because you are correct that we will not
be filling that position.
>> Okay.
>> I'll give you some kudos because there
were not a ton of red lines in any of
those. So that was appreciated
appreciated by me.
>> There will be at the next one of course
before we pass it to Thank you
Councilman Tina for catching that.
>> Okay. So
all of those are going through readings.
So again any questions pop up we have
plenty of time to ask. Um Mr. Mr. Als
you're my second on 6162.
>> Yes.
>> And then Mr. Sully is 63, 64, 65, and
66.
Perfect. I don't know what you were
doing, but works out.
Temporary ordinance 6725 that is coming
through finance as well. Um, this is our
yearly 80 road tiff. If Miss Nettles
wants to chime in here, that'd be great.
Yes, this is what um a few meetings back
that I um stated was would be coming.
It's our annual. We have two um tiff
notes that that are continuing to pay
off with the tiff proceeds. So, no
general fund monies are used to pay down
these notes to the developers. So, this
is the um developer notes that keep
getting paid down by those um tiff
settlement payments for the ed road
tiff. So this is kind of just the annual
piece that we're paying some of the
principal and renoting the remaining
balance.
>> That goes for 67 and 68. Correct.
>> Correct. Yes. Both of them.
>> Those two pieces, yearly pieces. Anyone
have any questions on those?
And I have Mr. Als on both.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
All right. That is all of the new
resolutions and ordinances we have for
tonight. I will ask for department
updates if we have anyone wanting to
give a department update.
You already talked too much. You can't
go.
>> Ouch.
Just a couple of updates. I know that we
kind of talked about this in our
administrative services meeting earlier
uh last week, but I also wanted to make
certain that all of council heard. We
are trying to give you quarterly updates
right now because we started the new uh
urgent care the free urgent care
services for city employees. So just
wanted to give you another update
because we ended our second quarter and
we got an update 664
visits so far from city employees and or
family members. Um that is a savings of
$16,600
in co-pays for our employees. So I
thought that was worth mentioning to you
on council floor.
Even after what we are paying in our
contract for Fairfield Medical Center,
we've still saved our health insurance a
minimum of $11,865.
And that's just assuming that it would
have been just a base a base fee at a
minimum. Um, considering all the other
factors that go into billing, it's
probably much more than that. But at a
minimum, we've already saved our health
insurance $11,865.
And like I said, we've saved our
employees $16,600
in co-pays. So that's worth mentioning.
Also, our mental health clinic,
we have saved our employees, we have
we've had 68 visits or 68
taking advantage of the mental health
clinic, which has saved $1,700 in
co-pays for mental health visits. And I
know that that doesn't sound
outstanding, but if you think about
before
our EAP services that the city has had
for many, many years, we had less than a
a 2% utilization rate. Given our current
numbers, we're almost at a 10% util
utilization rate for mental health
counseling right now by providing free
mental health counseling services. And I
know I've received numerous calls from
employees just openly, willingly sharing
their experience and saying thank you
for providing this for them. I know that
the mayor has received calls and our HR
coordinator Danielle has also received
calls thanking us for this service. So
again, I just thought that that was
worth me mentioning to you on council
floor. The last thing that I will share
with you is that our city employees are
once again for a third year trying to
win the trophy for the United Way 5K,
having the most participation for
employers that have over a 100
employees. Yes, county. We have won the
trophy now two years in a row and we're
going for three.
So far, we have 30.
>> I'm never going to be on a 5K. So,
you're safe. Hey, there is a two-mile
walk and we would encourage you uh to
sign up as part of our city team and
walk the two miles. We have plenty of
city employees that are going to be
walking the two miles instead of running
the 5K
>> right past your house, too. President
Porter, uh but right now we have 34 uh
people that are registered to
participate and support our United Way
in this event. So, we're really excited
about that. And as council members, if
you are interested in joining us to
either walk or run, please let me know.
We'd love to have you on the team.
>> I will do it and I'm challenging all of
you to do it.
>> A lot of witnesses. I've got Becky Tiner
down. Thank you.
>> What date is this?
>> Don't look at him looking at me.
>> It is Saturday, November 8th.
>> I want to come to Jeff's house and way
back.
>> We could all go.
>> I have some
eight. The route does go right beside
his house. So,
>> just saying we could pick him up on the
way.
>> Are you going to go?
>> No.
>> You going to No,
>> I'm already done with my walk.
>> I feel like I'm just waiting for Mr.
Porter to say, "Well, there'll be
mimosas at my house, so we can wave at
everybody walking by."
>> Well, that would be our drink as we walk
by.
>> Rather sit there.
Sorry.
>> Okay, we're getting out of control here,
but I'm out. Um, so, okay.
No. Any other department updates?
No. Brought up alcohol in the room. Just
went like
>> No.
>> Okay. I will kick it to Mr. Porter for
meeting prep.
>> Um the only thing out of the ordinary
this evening is our one ordinance of
council as a whole. Um doing the pre
presentation to the Sherman Rotary. When
we do get there and assuming that we
have a positive vote on that, we would
like any representatives in the audience
to come up and do a brief presentation
with the mayor and serve a safety
director. So,
>> who's one?
>> So, that's it. Great. Any other
discussion items for finance?
Seeing none, I would ask for a motion to
adjurnn.
>> So moved. Second
>> motion and a second and we are adjourned
at 6:31.
>> The regular meeting of Lancaster City
Council will commence at 6:40.
The Frankie Smith Funeral Home and
Crematory in Lancaster and the Johnson
Smith Funeral Home in Baltimore have a
long and wonderful history of serving
our community. Feel free to give us a
call at 74-653652.
Stop in and see us at either of our two
locations, 405 North Columbus Street in
Lancaster and 207 South Main Street in
Baltimore. Respect for tradition. Regard
for change.
>> Hi, this is the Senic family with the
Salvation Army of Fairfield County. Our
mission is to meet human needs without
discrimination. We provide a multitude
of services that focus on senior care
and preparing our youth for successful
futures. This month, we are excited to
be chosen by the Buckeye Automotive
Families Buckeye Cares program. They'll
make a donation with each car sold this
month. Thank you, Buckeye family, for
supporting the Salvation Army of
Fairfield County.
A moment of prayer. God, grant us the
serenity to accept the things that we
cannot change, the courage to change the
things we can, and finally the wisdom to
know the difference.
I now call the October 20th Lancaster
City Council meeting to order. Please
join me in the pledge of allegiance. I
pledge algiance to the flag of the
United States of America and to the
republic for which it stands, one nation
under God, indivisible, with liberty and
justice for all.
Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als here,
>> Mr. Bishack
>> here.
>> Mrs. Kes
>> Mrs. Hoop
>> here.
>> Mr. Lockenberg
>> Mr. Skunover
>> here.
>> Mr. Sully
>> Miss Teener
>> here.
>> And Mr. Wing
>> Let the record reflect that all nine
members of Lancaster City Council are
present. Reading and disposing of the
journal. Regular meeting minutes dated
October 6th, 2025.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the journal.
>> Second.
>> A motion, a second to receive and file
the journal. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> All those opposed, same sign. Reports of
city officials.
>> I have eight of them. Uh, email dated
October 3rd, 2025 regarding October 9th
planning commission meeting submitted by
city planner Chasing Carter. Email dated
October 8th, 2025 regarding revised
short-term rental code submitted by city
planner Chas Carter. Email dated October
13, 2025 regarding the September 2025
revenue report submitted by income tax
commissioner Amy Hamilton. series of
emails um dated October 15 through the
16th, 2025 regarding Sherman Rotary
resolution of expression submitted by
President Porter, service safety
director Carrie Woody and law director
Stephanie Hall. Email dated October 17,
2025 regarding November planning
commission meeting submitted by city
planner Chasing Carter. Email dated
October 17, 2025 regarding proposed
energy grant submitted by environmental
engineering engineer Denise Cruz. Email
dated October 20th, 2025 regarding
proposed energy grant submitted by storm
water manager Steven Welstead. A series
of emails dated October 17 through the
20th of 2025 regarding non-UN pay
submitted by council member Als and and
auditor Trisha Halls. Patricia Halls. I
mean, I'm sorry. I am blending your
names. It's Patricia Nettles.
>> Sorry.
Is she your boss?
>> Whoever you are.
>> It's not like you worked five feet
apart.
>> She was your boss.
>> That was the last one.
>> Yeah, that was the last.
>> Okay.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the reports of city
officials.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion to second to receive
and file the reports of city officials.
All those in favor, please signify by
saying I. I.
>> All those opposed, same sign. Now to
communication.
>> I have two email dated October 20th,
2025 regarding Google customer services
submitted by Stephanie Bosco with
Langster Port Authority. An email dated
October 20th, 2025 regarding copies for
past legislation
submitted by Zach Gerald with Columbus
Business First.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the communications.
>> Second. We have a motion and a second to
receive and file the communications. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> All those opposed, same sign,
>> special presentation and awards.
>> There are no petitions or I'm sorry,
there are no special presentations this
evening.
>> Okay. Petitions and memorials.
>> There are no there are none.
>> Thank you. We have now reached the time
in the meeting uh where we allow uh for
permission of voters and taxpayers to
address council. Um, you have a
threeminut time period and if you choose
to address council, if you come to the
podium, uh, you submit your name and
address. Are there any individuals here
this evening that would like to address
council?
Seeing none, we thank you for coming.
Reports of standing committees.
>> I have three. Safety committee meeting
agenda dated October 9th, 2025 submitted
by Mr. Bisjek. Water water pollution
committee meeting meeting agenda dated
October 17, 2025 submitted by Mr. Wing.
Um finance committee meeting agenda
dated October 20th, 2025 submitted by
Mr. Skunover.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the reports of
standing committees.
>> Second. We
>> have a motion and second to receive and
file the reports of standing committees.
All those in favor, please signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> All those opposed, same sign. Reports of
uh special committees. There are no
>> public hearings. There are none this
evening. We will now move to the reading
of resolutions. We'll begin with the
third reading of temporary resolution
7925.
>> A resolution to authorize the service
safety director to apply for a grant
through the Ohio Public Works Commission
to fund the Reese Avenue and West Hubert
Avenue rehabilitation project and to
declare an emergency. This is through
public works committee, Miss Tiner and
Mr. Lockenberg.
>> Council member team.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
the council pass and gross and enter
upon the written record temporary
resolution 7925.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and second to pass
gross and enter upon the written record
temporary resolution 7925.
Any discussion? Council member Tiner.
>> Yes. Is to apply for a grant to uh do
the uh project for Reese and uh West
Hubert Avenue. uh long time coming and
it'll be done soon to get the roads and
that repaired.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Bischack,
>> Mrs. Kit,
>> yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> Mr. Lochenberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> Mr. Sully,
>> yes.
>> Miss Ter,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Temporary resolution 7925
passes 9 to zero. Temporary resolution
8025. A resolution to authorize the
service safety director to advertise for
bids and enter into contracts for mowing
and trimming the city cemeteries. This
is through public works committee, Miss
Tiner and Mrs. Kretz.
>> Council member Tiner.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
that council pass and gross and enter
upon the written record temporary
resolution 8025.
>> Second.
>> You have a motion and second to pass and
gross and enter upon the written record
temporary resolution 8025. Discussion.
Council member Tiner.
>> Yes. This is just so that the cemetery
can uh and trimming for the cemeteries
can get done next year. So, it's just
going out for bid.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
>> Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bishack, yes.
>> Mrs. Kra, yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Loenberg,
>> Mr. Skoonover,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Ter, yes.
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Temporary resolution 8025 passes 9 to
zero. Temporary resolution 8125.
A resolution to authorize the law
director to negotiate and enter into a
contract with the city of Reynoldsburg
for the prosecution of adult misdemeanor
traffic and criminal offenses committed
in the city of Reynoldsburg within
Fairfield County, Ohio and to accept
payment for the same. Through finance
committee, Mr. Skunover, Mr. Als,
>> council member Spoonover.
>> Mr. President, I like to make a motion
that council pass and gross and enter
upon written record temporary resolution
8125.
Second. We
>> have a motion and second to pass and
gross and enter upon the written record
temporary resolution 8125. Discussion.
Council member Skunover.
>> Uh, no. Thank you.
>> Any further discussion?
>> Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> yes.
>> Mrs. Kra,
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Leterberg,
>> Mr. Scooper,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Teener, yes. And Mr. Wink,
>> yes.
>> Temporary resolution 8125 passes 9 to
zero. We now move on to the second
reading of resolutions beginning with
temporary resolution 8325.
>> A resolution to make appropriations for
planned 2026 budget expenses and other
expenditures of the city of Lancaster
for fiscal year 2026 and to establish
line item transfer authority for all
city departments. This through finance
committee, Mr. Skunover and Mr. Sully.
>> Council member Skunover. That's a second
of three readings, please. Second of
three readings on temporary resolution
8325.
Temporary resolution 8425.
>> A resolution to increase and decrease
appropriations in the general fund
for the Lancaster Fire Department
overtime and to declare an emergency.
This is through safety committee. Mr.
Bisjack and Miss Tiner.
>> Council member Bisjack.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. This is the
second of three readings.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
resolution 8425.
Temporary resolution 8525,
>> a resolution to appropriate from the
unencumbered balance in the health
insurance management fund 7022 to amend
the certificate of appropriations with
the Fairful County Auditor and to
declare an emergency. Mr. Administrative
Services Committee, Mr. Luckenberg and
Mr. Bisjack,
>> Council Member Luckenberg.
>> Second of three readings, please.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
resolution 8525.
We now move on to the first reading of
resolutions beginning with temporary
resolution 8725.
>> A resolution authorizing the mayor to
prepare and submit an application to
participate in the Ohio Department of
Development Advanced Energy Fund Grant
Program to execute contracts as required
and to declare an emergency. This is
through water water pollution control
committee. Mr. Wing and Miss Tiner.
>> Council member Wing.
>> Yes, Mr. President. And I move that
council suspend its rules and wave the
second and third reading of temporary
resolution number 8725.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to suspend
the rules and wave the second and third
reading of temporary resolution 8725.
Discussion. Council member Wing.
>> Yes. The reason for this is we have a
deadline October 31st and we need to
heat the Southwater plant.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion
hearing? None. Please call the role on
the motion to suspend.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bishjack. Yes.
>> Mrs. K. Yes. Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Lockenberg,
>> Mr. Skoover,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Tiner,
>> yes.
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> Motion to suspend the rules and wave the
second and third reading of temporary
resolution 8725. Passes 9 to zero.
Council member Wing.
>> Yes. Thank you, Mr. President. I move
that council pass engross and enter upon
the written record. Temporary resolution
number 8725.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and second to pass and
gross and enter upon the written record
temporary resolution 8725. Any further
discussion?
>> Nothing further. Thank you. Uh, please
call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes. Mr. Bisjack, yes. Mrs.
Kit, yes.
>> Mrs. Who?
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Lockenberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> Mr. Sully,
>> yes.
>> Miss Ter, yes.
>> And Mr. W.
>> Yes.
>> Motion to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record. Temporary resolution
8725 passes 9 to zero. No. Temporary
resolution 8825. A resolution
recognizing the Lancaster Sherman Rotary
for its volunteer time, hours, and
dedication to the community and
honorarily
designating Center Alley as Sherman
Rotary Alley and to declare an
emergency. This is council of a whole.
Um, Mr. Skunover and Miss Tiner.
>> Yes, Mr. President. I'd like to make a
motion that council suspend its rules
and wave the second and third readings
of temporary resolution 8825.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to suspend
the rules and wave the second and third
reading of temporary resolution 8825.
Any discussion?
>> No, sir.
>> Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bishek, yes.
>> Mrs. Kit, yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Lockenberg,
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Ter,
>> yes.
>> And Mr. Wink,
>> yes. Motion to suspend the rules and
wave the second and third reading of
temporary resolution 8825 passes 9 to
zero. Council member Skunover.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to pass engross and enter upon the
written record temporary resolution
8825.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to pass
and gross and enter upon the written
record temporary resolution 88.25.
Any further discussion?
>> Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes. Mr. Bishack, yes.
>> Mrs. Kes, yes. Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Mr. Luckenberg.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Skunover.
>> Mr. Sully.
>> Yes.
>> Miss Tiner. Yes. And Mr. Wing.
>> Temporary resolution 8825. Passes 9 to
zero. And now at this time, if the
members of the Sherman Rotary could join
uh the city officials up here in the
front, we'll get a photo. And I think
that the mayor has a presentation.
I hate the pictures
out.
>> You draft Another
[Music]
second row here.
Who do you want over here? Who needs to
be over here?
>> Probably.
>> Kristen for a while.
>> Trust me.
>> He does what he's told. All right.
>> Put your heads in.
>> Just put your heads in it.
That was the practice.
>> I think I'm blank.
>> Did I mess up your names?
I noticed it when I rewatched the
videos.
>> I already
so weird how all this work green over on
this side.
>> Well, I'll take it.
>> Thank you everybody. It's not often that
we get to recognize such level of
service uh public service, but um we
were very thankful to do that tonight
and thanks to the mayor and service
safety director Woody for that
opportunity. We appreciate that. So, and
we appreciate everything you guys do as
well. Thank you.
We're now going to move back into uh the
agenda with the first reading of
temporary resolution 8925,
>> a resolution to authorize the service
safety director to enter into a contract
not to exceed $500,000 with aR
architecture for design and construction
administration of the Ed Road fire
station project and to declare an
emergency. This is through safety
committee, Mr. Mr. Bisjack and Miss
Tiner.
>> Council member Bisjack.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. This is the
first of three readings.
>> First of three readings on temporary
resolution 8925.
We now move on to the reading of
ordinances. Beginning with the third
reading of temporary ordinance 4925,
>> an ordinance to establish benefits,
titles, and compensation for parks and
recreation personnel employed by the
city of Lancaster, Ohio for the year
2026 and to declare an emergency. Mr.
Administrative Services Committee, Mr.
Luenberg and Mr. Mr. Bischek.
>> Council member Luck.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. President. I'd like
to make a motion that council place on
the table uh ordinance temporarily
numbered 87
uh 8525
>> 495
>> 4925. We'll get you right.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion second to place on the
table temporary ordinance 4925. This is
a non-debatable motion. Please call the
role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bishack, yes.
>> Mrs. Kit.
>> Yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop.
>> Mr. Lockenberg.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Screenover.
>> Mr. Sully.
>> Yes.
>> Miss Tiner.
>> And Mr. Wing.
>> Yes.
>> Temporary ordinance 4925 is laid upon
the table uh by a vote of 9 to zero.
>> Temporary ordinance 5125.
An ordinance providing for the issuance
and sale of notes in the maximum
principal amount of $180,000
in the anticipation of the issuance of
bonds for the purpose of paying the cost
of the renovation of an existing
building for use by the city's municipal
court together with all necessary
thereto and declare an emergency this
through finance committee Mr. Skunover
and Mr. Sully.
>> Council member Skunover.
>> Mr. President like to make a motion that
council pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary ordinance
5125.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to pass
and gross and enter upon the written
record temporary ordinance 5125.
Discussion.
>> I don't have any.
>> Thank you. Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack, yes.
>> Mrs. K. Yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Lockenberg.
>> Mr. Scoover.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Sully.
>> Miss Ter. Yes.
>> And Mr. W.
>> Yes. Temporary ordinance 51-25 passes 9
to zero. Temporary ordinance 5325.
An ordinance to amend Lancaster codified
ordinance part five general offenses
code and adopt chapter 550 fireworks.
It's through law committee. Mrs. Kates
and Mr. Bisjek.
>> Council member K.
>> Yes. Thank you, Mr. President. I would
like to make a motion that council pass
and gross and I would like to make a
motion that council pass and gross and
enter upon the written record. Ordinance
temporarily numbered 53-25.
>> Second. We have a motion in a second to
pass and gross and enter upon the
written record. Temporary ordinance
5325.
Discussion. Council member Kits.
>> Yes. Thank you. Just briefly. Uh this
legislation will help the city better
control public displays of fireworks by
restricting them to ex exhibitions
run by appropriate individuals and
businesses who are licensed and meet uh
proper permit criteria.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
>> Mr. President, could be recognized,
please?
>> Yes, Mr. Mayor.
>> I just want to remind uh members of
council that uh the police department,
fire department, and the city
administration support this legislation.
I think it's safe to say there's
probably no place in the city of Lanster
that we can currently legally set off
fireworks according to state law. This
just allows a better tool to enforce
violations should they occur.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Any further
discussion?
>> I do have one last item that I did want
to mention, please.
>> Um, we have also received communications
from members of the public supporting
this legislation who were unable to come
and speak at a council me and I just
wanted to mention that.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion
hearing? None. Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bishek, yes.
>> Mrs. Kit, yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Lockenberg,
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> no.
>> Miss Tiner,
>> yes.
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> Temporary ordinance 5325.
Passes 8 to 1. Now move on to the second
reading of ordinances. Beginning with
temporary ordinance 5425,
>> an ordinance to authorize the service
safety director to enter into an FFFCC
notification for spectrum manager lease
and spectrum lease agreement with census
for the implementation of the smart
metering initiative by Lancaster
Municipal Gaps. Mr. Service Committee,
Mr. Als, and Mr. Wing.
>> Council member Als,
>> second of three readings, please. Second
of three readings on temporary ordinance
5425.
Temporary ordinance 5525.
>> An ordinance to establish the
compensation for the council president,
council members, and the council clerk
for the term commencing payroll 1 of
2026. This is through finance committee.
Mr. Skunover and Mr. Sully.
>> Council member Skunover.
>> Second of three readings, please.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5525.
Temporary ordinance 5625.
an emergency ordinance declaring the
improvement to certain parcels
associated with the Sheridan Drive
project in the city to be a public
purpose and exempt from taxation
pursuant to OC5709.40B
40B requiring the owners of those
parcels to make service payments in lie
of taxes.
Authorizing the city to require minimum
service payments, and such payments are
agreed upon by developer, establishing a
municipal public improvement tax
increment equivalent fund for the
deposit of those service payments, and
as applicable, minimum service payments,
authorizing payments to this Lancaster
City School District, specifying the
public infrastructure improvements that
directly benefit the parcels, and
approving related matters. Mr. Economic
Development Committee, Mrs. Hoop and
Mrs. K.
>> Council member Hoop.
>> Um, two or three readings, please.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5625.
Now move on to the first reading of
ordinances beginning with temporary
ordinance 5725.
>> An ordinance to establish the
compensation for the city treasurer for
the term commencing payroll 1, 2026, and
to declare an emergency. This through
finance committee, Mr. Skunover and Mr.
Mr. Als,
>> Council Member Skoonover.
>> First of three readings, please.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5725.
Temporary ordinance 5825,
>> an ordinance to adopt and enact the city
of Lancaster cyber security program
pursuant to the Ohio Revised Code,
Chapter 9, Miscellaneous Section 9.64,
Political Subdivision, Cyber Security.
This is through law committee. Mrs. Kitz
and Mr. Bisjek.
>> Council member K.
>> First of three readings. First of three
readings on temporary ordinance 5825.
We'll now move on to temporary ordinance
through
um let's see here's
not that one yet.
>> Oh, okay. All right. Yep. Sorry. Uh move
on to the temporary ordinance 5925. An
ordinance to amend the city of
Lancaster's zoning map to change the
zoning of 35.506
plus or minus acres identified as Fairfo
County auditor tax parcel number
0534162500
from plan unit development district to
residential medium density district.
This is through code enforcement and
code enforcement and zoning committee.
Mr. Sully and Miss H.
>> Council member Sulli first of three
readings please. First of three readings
on temporary ordinance 5925.
We'll now move on to
uh temporary ordinance 6025.
>> An ordinance to amend the Lancaster
codified ordinances part 11 planning and
zoning title 3 zoning and property
restrictions and to adopt chapter 1131
short-term rentals. Again, this is
through code enforcement and zoning
committee Mr. Sully and Mr. Lockenberg.
>> Council member Sie. First of three
readings, please.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 6025. We'll now move on to the
first reading of temporary ordinances
6125, 6225,
6325, 6425,
6525, and 6625.
an ordinance to establish the benefits,
titles, and compensation for management
and professional personnel employed by
the city of Lancaster, Ohio for the 20
the year 2026 and to declare an
emergency. That's finance committee, Mr.
ALS um 6225 an ordinance to establish
benefits, titles, and compensation for
those employees who are not members of
this recognized bargaining units
employed by the city of Lancaster, Ohio
for the year 2026 and to declare an
emergency. This again is through finance
committee, Mr. Scoover, Mr. Hills.
Um, temporary ordinance 6325, an
ordinance to establish the benefits,
titles, and compensation for seasonal
interns and to be employed by the city
of Lancaster during the summer of 2026
and to declare an emergency. This is
through finance committee, Mr. Skunover
and Mr. Sully. Uh temporary ordin
ordinary
temporary ordinance 6425 an ordinance to
establish the benefits titles and
compensation for the information
technology administrator office of the
clerk of court employed by the city of
Lancaster Ohio commencing the first pay
period of 2026 and to declare an
emergency again this is through finance
committee Mr. Skoover and Mr. Sully
temporary ordinance 6525 an ordinance to
establish the benefits titles and
compensation for the Fairfield County
Municipal Court management and
professional
personnel employed by the city of
Lancaster, Ohio for the year 2026 and to
declare an emergency. This is through
finance committee Mr. Skinner, Mr.
Sully. And the last one is temporary
ordinance 6625, an ordinance to
establish benefits, titles, and
compensation for Fairfolk County
Municipal Court judicial and probation
personnel employed by the city of
Lancaster, Ohio for the year 2026 and to
declare an emergency. And again, this is
through finance committee, Mr. Skoover
and Mr. Sully.
>> Council member Skunover.
>> The first of three readings on all of
those, please.
>> Thank you. First of three readings on
temporary ordinance 6125,
6225, 6325, 6425, 6625,
and 6525.
Uh temporary ordinance 6725,
>> an ordinance providing the issuance of
the sale of revenue notes in the
aggregate principle of amount of 61,427
to pay the cost of improving Ed Road,
Memorial Drive, and Michael's Way by
grading, widening, paving, curving, and
improving bridges and railroad
crossings, relocating utilities, and
installing sidewalks. traffic signals
and signs and water sanitary and storm
water lines and facilities together with
all necessary importancees
there too and to declare an emergency.
This is through finance committee Mr.
Skunover and Mr. Als.
>> Council member Skunover. First of three
readings, please.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 6725, temporary ordinance
6825. An ordinance providing the
issuance of the sale of a revenue note
in the aggregate principal amount of
180,86,5758
to reimburse Flagstar Bank NA for a draw
on the letter of credit in the
connection with the cost of improving Ed
Road, Memorial Drive, and Michael's Way
by grading, widening, paving, curbing,
and improving bridges and railroad
crossings, relocating utilities and
installing sidewalks, traffic signals
and signs and water sanitary and storm
water lines and facilities together with
all necessary importances
pertinances there too in declare an
emergency this through finance committee
Mr. Skunover and Mr. Als
>> council member Skunover
>> fortunately just the second of three
readings for
>> second of three
>> it's the first
See even worse.
>> First of three.
>> First of three readings for you.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 6825.
Um we have no further ordinances this
evening. We will move to uh table
legislation
um temporary ordinance 3125.
>> Do I need to do this in two votes or can
we remove it or move on?
>> I got to read it first. Drake,
>> what's the process?
>> Sorry. two votes. Uh motion to remove it
from the table and then a motion to
withdraw it.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. I'd like to
make a motion that we uh remove uh
ordinance 3125 off the table.
>> I second that.
>> We have a motion and second to remove
temporary ordinance 3125 from the table.
Non-debatable. Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> Mrs. K.
>> Yes.
>> Mrs. H.
>> Mr. Lenberg?
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Skunberg?
>> Yes. Mr. Sullie,
>> yes.
>> Miss Tiner,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Temporary ordinance 3125 is now removed
from the table. Uh, Council Member
Single.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. I'd like to
make a motion to withdraw uh temporary
ordinance 3125.
>> Second. Sorry.
>> We have a motion in a second to withdraw
temporary ordinance 3125.
Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bizch,
>> yes.
>> Mrs. Christ,
>> Mrs. H.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Mr. Luenberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> Mr. Sully,
>> yes.
>> Miss Tinder,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Temporary ordinance 3125
has been withdrawn.
Have no further um legislation this
evening. Move to unfinished business.
>> Okay, we have no unfinished business.
Move on to new business. Uh council
member reports. Uh I'll start with
council member Sie.
>> Nothing new to report.
>> Thank you. Council member Bisjack.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. President. October
10th, safety committee met. We discussed
the budgets of both the police and fire
departments. Uh, a lot of good dialogue,
a lot of great questions. Looking
forward to seeing what versions two and
three have, uh, for the council as a
whole. Um, looking forward to meet again
in December, uh, assuming a vote has not
happened, uh, for the city budget.
That's all I have. Thank you, Mr.
President.
>> Thank you, Council Member Lenber. Um,
yes, my committee met last week and
unfortunately I did not come prepared to
discuss what we discussed. So, okay,
>> I'll do that next week.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Well, yeah, two weeks.
>> Two weeks from now.
>> Okay. All right. Council member Als,
>> uh, we've met with all of the department
heads on the initial uh, reviews of
budgets. So, that went well.
>> Kind of.
>> Okay. Thank you very much, Council
Member Kates.
>> Uh, yes. The next law committee is
November 7th at 9:00 a.m. in the 1897
conference room in city hall. So far on
the agenda, we have the 2025 budget as
well as handicap parking spots.
>> Thank you, Council Member Tiner.
>> Uh we had our meeting back in um
September and I'd already reported that
the last meeting and our next meeting is
in November the 14th.
>> Thank you, Council Member Skonover.
>> Uh just the same thing that I've been
preaching about the budget. So
everybody's
got to look at it. Pay ordinances are in
front of us and make sure to gather and
ask your questions. That's all I got.
>> Thank you, Council Member Wing.
>> Yes. Thank you, Mr. President. Uh the
water and water pollution committee uh
last met this morning. Uh just a couple
of quick updates from that. Uh pleased
to report that uh startup is going well
at the North Water Plant, which is
great. And finally, the Main Street
sewer separation project is almost
finished. Uh by the end of the week it
uh will be just about done. All the pave
will be complete and um just some punch
list items will be left. So just about
done.
>> Good. Great news. Council member Hoop.
>> Thank you. Um economic development
committee meeting is next Thursday at
7:30 in the 1897
room.
>> Okay,
>> that's it.
>> All right. Thank you. Regularly
scheduled city council meetings.
I have um next regular sessions of
council November 3rd, 2025 at 6:30 p.m.
here in council chambers and then
November 17th, 2025 at 6:30 and here in
council chambers.
>> Thank you. And there are no special
scheduled meetings, regularly scheduled
committee meetings.
>> I have two three four five um five of
them. Economic development committee
meeting October 30th at 7:30 at city
hall 1897 conference room. Um, finance
committee meeting November 3rd at 6:00
pm in council chambers. Law committee
November 7th at 9:00 a.m. City Hall 1897
conference room. Uh, public works
committee meeting November 14th at 7:30
a.m. City Hall 1897 conference room.
Water pollution committee meeting
November 17th at 7:30 a.m. City Hall
1897 conference room. And then code
enforcement committee meeting November
20th at 7:30 a.m. at city hall 1897
conference room.
>> Thank you. Reading of bills.
>> I have one for NNCO for publications of
ordinances for $106.97.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
we pay the bill.
>> Second.
>> A motion a second to pay the bill. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> All those opposed, same sign. Bill is
paid. No need for an executive session.
I will now entertain a motion to
adjourn.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make that
motion we adjourn.
>> Second.
>> A motion and second to adjurnn. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I. All those opposed, same sign. Please
remember to sign your legislation before
you leave this evening. Thank you.
[Music]